I take it you know who I am
I do.
I know a lot of people didn't want you in
the Proving.
But if you hadn't been there,
everyone would've died.
Shows how much we know.
The very person we needed
was someone the tribe never wanted.
I wish I could borrow some of your courage now.
For him.
Nothing I do comforts him.
I don't even have any Dreamwillow to ease his pain.
There should be some in stashes along
Brave Trails to the east, but…
These will keep.
The Brave Trail.
Should be a cache of Dreamwillow up there.
No Dreamwillow, just a few shards.
I'll tuck that away.
Saving these for the trail.
Might be a cache of Dreamwillow along that Brave Trail.
Strange.
Looks like someone swapped all
the Dreamwillow in these caches for shards.
There's no Dreamwillow in these caches.
Fia will want to know.
You're back.
I've already been to those stashes.
All I found was a few shards.
That's strange, who would have taken the Dreamwillow?
It's possible that Jun has gathered more.
He may be a recluse but he helps the tribe
by picking herbs and brewing medicines.
The problem is that he lives west of Mother's Crown,
and machines in that region are troublesome.
What sort of machines?
Scrappers and Sawtooths.
It's quite dangerous.
You could ask him if you're willing to make
the journey.
I'll be on my way.
Of course.
[praying Nora]
Goddess please. We are your faithful children.
Show us mercy.
Keep quiet now.
Tough, but i'm used to it.
Down you go!
Just stand by for now.
Snow haze, white as bone.
Huh, that thought got dark.
Look out below!
[in the distance]
Help!
[in the cabin]
I'm locked in!
Someone!
[in the cabin]
Is someone there?
All-Mother be praised!
I thought I'd never be freed.
What happened?
A gang of outcasts, that's what.
They burst in, stole my Dreamwillow,
and left me to die.
A "gang" of outcasts?
Yes a gang.
The door crashed open, I didn't stand a chance.
They grabbed my Dreamwillow and left me for dead.
Why would outcasts steal your Dreamwillow?
Why?
Because it's the most valuable
herb I gather of course.
Miserable thieves.
They took nothing else?
No.
Mark my words they have struck a deal with outsiders.
It's shards they're after and they'll kill to get it.
Which way did the outcasts go?
Up the mountain I think.
You might catch them if you hurry.
Whatever you do, don't let their shabby looks fool you.
They'll kill you as soon as look at you.
Uhhh, I need to catch my breath.
Yeah, you could stop talking for a start.
The outcasts must have left tracks.
My Focus should pick them up.
Well someone left here recently, and they were in a hurry.
[in the distance]
Got it!
Hit it again!
[in the distance]
I'm out of arrows.
The outcasts that took the Dreamwillow,
and they're in trouble.
[in the distance]
Kill it!
Finish it!
I can get out of this.
[in the distance]
Don't lose your target!
I'm out!
[in the distance]
Yes!
You hurt it!
[in the distance]
All-Mother be praised!
Good shot!
[in the distance]
You have our thanks, if the gratitude
of outcasts means anything to you.
It does.
You not only save us but speak to us.
The Matriarchs cast me out at birth.
The laws of the Nora don't mean much to me.
Then you're that girl whose mother never claimed her.
But an outcast no longer.
No. A Seeker in fact.
What crimes did you and the others commit?
I beat a man who stole my kill, it was my wrong.
The others stole, broke custom, or trespassed
among the bones of the Metal World.
No murderers here if that's what you're asking.
Why did you take the Dreamwillow?
Because we have wounded.
Why else would we take it?
Something terrible has happened to the tribe.
The Braves offer no protection.
The machines are angry and bandits infest
the Sacred Land and prey upon us.
Why else would outcasts break custom and band
together but that we have no choice.
Even so, we did not steal.
We left shards in the stashes, and tried to pay Jun.
But of course he would not speak to us.
Jun said you roughed him up.
He was too busy cringing to know what happened.
The man's a coward.
We made sure not to hurt him,
not that he seemed to notice.
There are others who need Dreamwillow,
you can't have all of it.
You asking or demanding?
Talking.
One person to another.
I see.
Perhaps we have more than we need.
After everything that happened we were afraid.
We took all we could find.
Here.
I'll keep a portion but the rest…
May it find its way to those who need it.
I'll see that it does.
In the meantime stay safe and stick together.
You gave us a better deal than
the Matriarchs ever would have, thanks.
Here's the Dreamwillow.
Take it to Fia in Mother's Rise.
There are wounded Braves there who need it badly.
I will, but what became of the outcasts?
Did those wretches pay for their crimes?
Ganging up together,
speaking to each other, and to us!
I hope you showed them no mercy.
It's funny how you hate outcasts so much Jun.
Living out here all alone you're practically
one yourself.
I happily keep my own company.
Good for you, since I don't exactly see anyone
beating down the door to spend time with you.
Except outcasts in need of Dreamwillow that is.
You don't know who I am do you?
Should I?
I was raised as an outcast
in the mountains above Mother's Heart.
The motherless girl!
If I'd known I never would have spoken to you.
And yet it's this "motherless girl" who freed you
and recovered your Dreamwillow for the tribe.
Maybe if you judged people less
you wouldn't be so lonely.
I have no need of others.
Then congratulations Jun, you've managed to shun yourself.
At least I'm no outcast.
That's right, you're not even that.
The outcasts reached out to each other, but you?
You're nothing!
I'm done here.
Make sure that Fia gets that Dreamwillow or I'll be back.
These'll keep.
They're scanning for me.
Oh, useful.
Mother's Crown.
Feels more like a military camp.
I bet this village has seen better days.
So many wounded, the tribe's been hit hard.
[wounded Nora]
I hope I never see a corrupted machine again.
Here she is!
They made her a Seeker!
Come here girl, let's have a look at you.
The girl with the mark of a Seeker.
The sentinels saw you coming.
You're Marea, so you're in charge of the defenses here.
Mother's Crown defends itself.
During the war it survived fifteen assaults,
broke three invasions.
We will endure.
Trying to live up to glorious pasts has a
way of getting people killed.
You wouldn't know this
but I won the Proving the year I ran.
Like you I started off behind, had to find a shortcut.
I barely made it.
Crossed the finish line with a broken ankle.
Getting posted to Mother's Crown,
it was the boon I requested.
My prize for winning.
Trying to live up to the glory of the Nora hasn't killed me yet.
But if it has to, I'm willing.
Mother's Crown guards the edge of the Sacred Land, right?
So do you see a lot of foreigners here?
Yes.
Not here in the village itself of course.
But in the valley beyond.
Since the war ended foreigners have been allowed in the valley,
and Nora can trade with them if they choose.
It's a kind of in-between place, neither foreign nor Sacred Land.
If you're curious visit Hunter's Gathering.
It's little more than a heap of dingy shelters and tents,
but foreigners use it as a way station.
Varl told me you'd know the way to Meridian.
The Carja capital?
West will take you to it.
But their soldiers will stop you long before you get there.
They can try.
No, what I mean is there's a Carja fort
that guards the pass between east and west.
Word is the Carja have sealed the gate,
out of fear of the corrupted machines
infesting our Sacred Land.
The Carja call the place Daytower.
It's not far from the forsaken village.
What forsaken village?
It had a name once, not that it matters now.
I was born there.
What happened to it?
The war.
The Carja destroyed it in one of their Red Raids.
I was 15 at the time.
I got away, others weren't so lucky.
Even now with the war behind us we've left the valley be.
A kind of buffer between the Sundom and our Sacred Land.
How far has the corruption spread?
I've seen it myself in machines at the head of the valley.
And there's been word of corrupted machines in the south too.
Whatever the corruption is it doesn't just affect machines.
It burns flesh and sickens the injured.
Do the corrupted machines have any weaknesses?
Fire seems to affect them more than ordinary machines.
A small mercy.
This is a curse only the Goddess can lift.
Unless we find out what's behind it and put a stop to it.
The Matriarchs have spoken, Aloy.
All we can do is fight and pray to the Goddess.
I should be going.
All right.
Be careful out there Aloy.
I hope you find whatever it is you're after.
Solai should be around here somewhere
Are you Solai?
Yan said your niece may have come through here, Nakoa?
I've got nothing to say about that.
Please, I only want to help.
I'm a Seeker, headed north.
Yan wanted me to help find her.
Anything you tell me stays between us.
I've…
I gave her supplies for the journey.
She was headed for Daytower, looking for Zaid.
I told Nakoa not to go.
What's a lone Nora gonna do there?
Bastards used to gather Nora captives there,
so they could ship them to Meridian for slaughter.
What do you know of Zaid?
He's a rabid animal, a murderer.
The worst of the Red Raiders.
Killed my brother while poor Nakoa watched from the shadows.
Even as I begged her not to go, part of me wanted her to.
I need him dead as much as she does.
I understand, better than you think.
You can't imagine what it's like.
He … he mutilated my brother and yet he walks free among the Carja!
I'll look for Nakoa when I reach Daytower.
Just don't mention why you're asking.
I won't, I promise.
Oh it's you.
The outcast turned Seeker.
I've heard you're good with bow and spear.
Yeah, some even say you're the best.
I think I hear a challenge in there somewhere,
and I'm not interested.
I have more important things to do.
Oh, I see.
The Seeker doesn't have time for us lesser Nora.
Too busy hunting machines and marauders.
Do you try to provoke everyone you talk to?
Well I can't claim to have faced the corrupted,
or danced with demons.
But I have earned a few suns at
the Hunting Grounds at Valleymeet.
I took down machines with three different
types of arrows, freeze, shock, and fire.
Have you?
Or maybe your seeking hasn't taken you that far.
Is that even in the Sacred Lands?
Depends on who you ask.
It used to be ours but since the Red Raids ended,
the border is a bit … unclear.
The keeper's a Carja.
He can't refuse anyone the trials but don't come on too strong.
If your seeking takes you to the Hunting Grounds
you'd better come equipped.
But I'm sure a Seeker is always prepared, right?
See if you can earn a Blazing Sun.
If you do, you'll know you beat me.
Consider it done.
[in the distance]
My own damn fault, I should have got out of there quick.
What happened to you, Hunter?
Are you all right?
Oh I'm grateful for this wound.
It's a lesson I won't forget, and you should heed it too.
How's that?
I was chasing a galloping Grazer.
So intent on my prey that I didn't see where I was going.
Right to the threshold of a Cauldron.
For a moment I was a child again,
rapt from stories told by Hunters at the campfire.
I had a powerful desire to see what was inside.
That's when the Watcher attacked.
Cauldrons are guarded, you see.
I barely fought it off and got this scrape as a reminder.
A "cauldron"? What's that?
Ah, you're from inside the Embrace, so you've never seen one.
A Cauldron is a sort of door, I guess.
No-one knows what lies beyond.
Whatever they are, they're forbidden.
We weren't meant to see what's inside.
I'll never waver again, this scar will see to that.
But for a moment you felt something, a sense of discovery.
Are you so sure that's a bad thing?
Has to be, right?
Or I wouldn't have been punished.
Where can I find this Cauldron?
My point is you shouldn't.
Then describe the place I should avoid.
You're a clever one, but not so clever
as to heed my warning I see.
Fine, you're grown, I can't stop you.
It's dead north of here, past the Red Drifts.
Just remember I told you to stay away.
[wounded Nora]
It's spreading. The corrupted machines they're everywhere.
The machines, they've been driven mad.
Might be fascinating if they weren't looking for me.
Ready or not…!